Jai Hind friends, once again welcome to
your own YouTube channel Jaikal Genius.
I am your host and friend K Yadav.  In today's
video, we will see how
we can get 15% interest annually by changing our funds i.e. by
changing the fund manager or by changing our
choices or by
changing our options, that is, from
whom can we get it
?  ROI i.e. from whom can we get ROI of 15%
?  Can be taken under NPS.  Who is that too?
Government employee.  When NPS was launched,
such options were
not available in 2004.  What was there in it was that as per the
wishes of the government i.e. PFRDA, it will do whatever it wants to
utilize your funds.
But gradually there were
changes in NPS and after the changes, there are
some things which
came in favor of the government employees.  Like
changing the fund manager, changing your choices
, whether to keep it active or auto.  Ok
?  What brought all these things?  It came
into the hands of a government employee.  Now
what is inside it that many government employees do
not know what Auto Choice is?
What is Active Choice?  What is a fund manager
?  So in this video, first of all we will
try to know
what is a fund manager?  After that we will find out
what is Active and Photo Choice?
And you must stay in the video from the beginning till the end
because this video
is very important for you all
because the way the Unified Pension
Scheme was brought by the government which has completely
failed, most of the employees are going to
remain in NPS and they do
not want to go to UPS and right now there is
no certainty about the coming of the Old Pension Scheme whether the
government employees will get the Old Pension Scheme or
not.  So I am going to give you a lot of
updates and a lot of information in this video.
So first of all
we will see what is auto choice and
active choice.  After that we
will see what a fund manager is and then
we will see how we can get a return of 15% annually.
Ok?
What even happens in what constitutes equity
?  Ok?  What are government bonds
?  What are corporate bonds?
Ok?  Then what is an asset class?
We will discuss all this in detail in this video
today.  Ok?  So what do we
do first?  Let's go back to our screen again.
See Investment Options
Under NPS Where did I download this PDF from
?  Downloaded from NPS site.
If you want to download it then
go to the NPS site.
It will be available to you there.  This
is a bit old but it
is enough to explain to you people because I will give you the new update
in it.  Ok
?  Now look, here we will talk about
who is a fund manager?  A fund manager is that
person.  You understand it in a way that
someone who has complete knowledge of finance.
How is that?  That he knows that right now, that is, right
now, there is going to be a downfall in equity.
Upward is about to come.   That
is, when will the stock market fall and when will it
rise.  Ok?  What is that they have
special abilities.  They are
financial people, that is, those people who are
educated and have experience of many years, 10, 15,
20 years, 25-25 years
about the market.
Now the government employee neither has the time to
manage his funds.  So
what PFRDA did was appoint a fund
manager.  Now there are total 11
types of fund managers.  Now fund managers,
here in this PDF you will find only eight
but that means three fund managers and what did they do
?  Added it.  How many total fund managers are there now
?  As of today, there are a total of 11
fund managers.  Ok?  And
how many are there in this PDF here?  There are eight.  So there
is no problem.  We will manage with this PDF
because
I will provide you all the new updates in it.
Ok?  So how many fund managers are there in total?  There
are 11.  Now you can select any of the 11.  There
were Birla, Sunlit, HDFC, ICI, Kotak,
okay, LIC, Reliance, SBI, UTI, and one DSP,
one Tata, in this way there were 10, 11
invested options, okay, what is there in it, the
employee has two
options in NPS, okay, that is, Active Choice and one
is Auto Choice, so in this we see
Active Choice Individual Funds, that is,
what is the meaning of Active Choice, what is there in it, in
Active Choice it is
that a government employee, that is, an employee who has
knowledge about finance.
Which choice can he make?  Active
choice can be chosen.  What happens inside this is
that you can avail this up to the age of 50. Let
me tell you a little more here
before explaining Active Choice.  Look here at Asset Class
E.  What does E mean?  Let me
explain it to you a little here.  E stands for
Equity and Related Instruments.
That means equity means that in a way
you have your money in the share market, what will be done with it
?  The investment will be made
in equity.  Ok?  So you
can simply understand that
your money is going to be invested in equity i.e. in the share market.
Correct?  After that the next class that
comes is C.  C stands for
Corporate Bonds.  What does C mean
here?  C stands for Corporate
Bond.  Ok?  And the meaning of G became
Government Bonds.  If I talk about
corporate bonds here, then there are corporate
bonds which give you 8 to 9%, what do they give
you?  Give returns.  Ok?  And EE
means equity.  In equity, there are
many funds which have given returns up to 20%.  By
how much percentage?  Of 20%.
I will show it to you further and you yourself will
say yes sir.  Ok?  And
what do government bonds give you at around 8%?  Gives interest rate.
Ok?  This is the asset class.  Asset class
means MBS, Reeds etc. AIF, your
money is invested in these.  Ok?  Is this
what happened?  Asset class.  You have nothing to do with asset classes.
Three
things are important to you.  Which ones are those?
Firstly, EE means equity, C means corporate
debt, like what do the
corporate, that is, all the business
houses, what do those business houses do that they
take their loan to
set up their business and from whom do they take the loan, they will take it
directly, from whom, from PF RDA,
what will PF RDA say to them, brother, what do we want, we want
9% interest rate, then
where is your money being invested, then it is being invested
in corporate debt, similarly
what does the government also need to run many schemes, it needs debt,
okay, so what does the
government also do, that is, it buys bonds.
That is, what does the government do? It
borrows money and what does it do in return, that
is, its interest is the interest rate which the
government pays.  That means the
government
pays an interest rate of around 8%.  Ok?
Similarly, let us now talk about
active choice in this.  What is in active choice
that you have the option available?
Before the age of 50, that is, till the age of 50, you
can assume that till the age of 50, 75% allocation,
that is, in which can you keep the allocation up to 75%
?  In which can up to 75% allocation be kept
?  Can be kept within equity.
Equity means, as I told you above,
you can invest money in the share market.
Your remaining 10% is left.  Where can you invest 10% of your money
?
Inside the corporate i.e. inside the corporate department.  Ok
?  The remaining 15% of your money is left.  What
can you do inside?  Under government securities,
you
can invest your money in bonds.   For example, let
me assume here that your total
corpus is ₹100.  So where did you invest ₹75 out of ₹100
?  You invested ₹75
in the share market.  Ok?  What did you invest ₹10 in
?  Inside Corporate.  And
where will your 15% money be invested?  Inside Government Bonds.  Till
when?  For 50 years.  Then after 50 years,
when your age will be 51 years, it will
gradually decrease in the same percentage.
As you get closer to retirement,
this 75% allocation that you have made in
equity will
gradually decrease and then it will
reach the minimum stage as
I am going to show you here in the PDF.
Ok?  Now look, here we have
told you the Equity Allocation Matrix for
Active Choice, that is, if a
person who has knowledge of share market or finance,
what should he choose?
Active choice should be chosen.  So what will happen in that is that
what is the 75%
allocation that you can keep in it for 50 years?   Can be
kept within equity.  Ok?  Then
51, then see how much will it remain after decreasing gradually
?  At 60 and above 60, only 50%
allocation will remain.  Ok?  This is done, that is,
active choice, that is, active
choice should choose an employee who is
financially expert.  Now it's done,
one auto choice is left.  What happens in auto choice is that the
employee is assumed to have
no knowledge of any kind.
Ok?  Now what will he do with the fund manager
?  While using the fund manager, he will
leave it to the fund manager to
invest his money anywhere.
But I have given you this option
that you can invest 75%, 50% or 25% of my money
in the share market.  Now, every
employee has a different risk taking capacity.
I assume that someone who has
some knowledge, that is,
in the case of share market, what he will do is that there are
three choices available in it.  Let me
explain further here first.  That means aggressive.
Then after that the second choice that comes will be
your moderate.
Which one will come to you after moderate?  Conservative.  Ok?
Conservative means that an employee does
not want to take any risk at all.  So
only 25% of that money will be invested in what
?  Will be invested in equity.
Ok?  And I assume I am
moderate.  Moderate, suppose an employee like me,
who does
not want much risk and also wants high returns,
what will he do?  Moderate means that the scheme will
adopt LC 50.  Ok?  And
what is an LC75?  What is LC 75
?  Aggressive.  Aggressive means
giving too much allocation to whom
?  Giving within equity.  Now look,
I am telling you here.  This
is an option inside Auto Choice.  LC 75 LC 75 As soon as
you go to NPS and
enter your email number etc. and open it, if
you want to change your choice then the
option Auto and Active will appear inside it.  As soon as
you select auto,
LC 75 will appear there.  LC 75 will be given to the employee
whose age is what?  That is, up to 35 or
less than 35.  So what can he do?
What will be the allocation of one of your assets
?  If the employee is below 35 years of age, then
75% of the money i.e. 75% of the money will be
invested in equity.  10% will be
in C class and 15% will be in which?   It will be
inside the Government Department.  Ok?
If we move forward like this.  Now look, it is
given completely here age wise.  You
can also see here
how it is being reduced gradually.
Ok?  That means from 75% to
when you retire at the age of 55 or
above, you
can keep only 15% of the money in which?  You
can keep it inside equity.  Gradually,
your money will increase within the government bonds.
Ok?  If I talk about LC 50, that is, those who
take moderate risks,
which one can you listen to?  LC 55
LC 55 LC 50 Sorry LC 50
means that 50% of your fund is
total 50%, in which can the allocation of the fund be kept
?  will keep it within equity.
In whom will he keep 30%?  That means it will
keep 20% in private bonds and 20% will be kept in government debt.
Ok?  In this way,
what will be its allocation gradually?   While
decreasing, that means where will it go?   That
means it will come down to 10%.  Similarly, if we
look at LC 25, it is called conservative.
Conservative Fund Conservative fund is one in which the
employee does not want to take any risk at all.
Wants to make a safe investment of his money.
What is it that
keeps 25% of his money in it for up to 35 years?  That means the
stock market keeps it within equity.
45% within corporate depth and
30% within asset class i.e. G.
What is the reason that corporate bonds
give slightly higher returns than
other bonds?  of government bonds.  Ok?  So
gradually, when he turns 37, he will be left with
23%.  Ok?  In this way it keeps
decreasing and in the end your money is left with 36% in
government bonds, 41% in C
and 23% in equity.
Ok?  In this way you have seen what
Auto Choice, Active Choice and Fund
Manager are.  Now what I am going to explain here further,
I will explain to you what it is.  The
most important thing I will
show you is how much
percentage return equity has given till now.
How much has the government bond given and how much has the corporate bond given.
Along with this, we will also
see which fund manager has
given how much return here.  Ok?  So let us first go to the
NPS website.
Ok
?  As soon as you type
NPS NPS return on Google,
you have to go to Google and directly type NPS
return.  Ok?  As soon as you submit your NPS returns,
which one will you switch to?  You will go
to NPS Trust.  So
what do you have to do with this on NPS Trust?  Have to click.
Ok?  So it will take some time to load.
My net is a bit slow today.  Ok
?  Wait a moment.  Let it load.
Look at returns under NPS where are we at?
Currently it is available on NPS Trust on NPS website.
Ok?  So here we will look at scheme
returns. We will talk about scheme returns.
So first of all we have selected here the
scheme category Scheme E Tier One
i.e. we are talking about equity.
Whatever we want to change from here, we
can select anything inside it.  Like
Scheme E Tier One Scheme E i.e. Corporate
Bond Tier One Scheme Government Bond Tier
One.  Ok?  We can select any one and
compare it to see
how much return we have received from which fund.
Ok?  What have we
done now?  We have chosen Scheme E Tier One.
So in this we will see which fund
manager has done the best work for
you people.  So see what the stock market was
doing for the last few days?   It was
down for six-seven months.  Even then you can
see.  The maximum amount that
I have
taken under NPS is one year.  You can compare 3 years, 5 years, 7 years, 10 years
within this.
In the last one year, DSP, i.e. the fund
manager, has given a
return of 22.73% in equity.  If you assume
that you will not change your fund then see
how much return SBI has given here, I will
show you.  SBI has given a return of only 5%.
Ok?  UTI has
given Rs 10.44.  Kotak has given it for Rs 11.57.
Whereas how much has the DSP given?  22.73% has been
given.  So I am telling you
why this video is important for you people
?  Because first of all you should
change your fund manager.  Everyone will have a
fund manager.  There will be SBI, there
will be UTI and which one is it?  There will be another one.  Yes,
LIC will run.  These will be the only three fund managers.  The
location of 333% must have been given by the government.
Because you did not select it.
Neither did auto nor activated it.   It
is standard.  In Standard,
your allocation is done within these three LIC, SBI and UTI at
33% each.  Ok?  Now,
if you assume that you had
chosen DSP last year, then
how much interest would you have earned on your money of Rs 1 lakh
?  I would have been getting Rs 22-23,000.
How much would 10 lakhs amount to?  It would have been ₹2.5 lakh.  Whereas
how much has happened in SBI?  Got 5%.
Correct?  Look at 3 years, here
you can see the comparison of 3 years.  Who is the
best fund manager seen here in the last 3 years
?  The best is
UTI 15.97 followed by Kotak.  Ok?
If we
look at its calculation within 5 years, then who is the best
fund manager I see here within 7 years
?  That is ICICI.  Ok?
What is the 23.70% interest given?  Returned.
So you see how much you get in corporate bonds
?  8% is fixed in 9% government bonds.
And look here,
what did you get for 23.70?  Returns have been received in the last 5 years.
If we talk about seven years, then
see, the return made in seven years is
13.82, the highest sorry 13.92
is made in HDFC.  Ok?  Then after that
UTI is formed inside.  Kotak has made the highest gain of 14%.
Ok?  So
look at it this way, how much
more returns you are getting here.
If we select 10 years here, then you will see that the
highest interest available here is Rs 12.50 in HDFC.
Ok?  After that, in UTI, then
in Kotak, since inception, that is,
how much return have these fund managers
given since they started?  Look DSP gave a return of 19.71%.
Ok?  Tata gave it for Rs 16.10.
So in this way, unless you change your fund manager
, unless you change your choice
, then where will you get the best returns in NPS
?  If you
want the best returns, what should you do first?
Change your fund manager.
What do you do after that?  Change your choice.
Select one of Auto or Active
and after selecting it, you can
choose any one of the three funds.  Ok
?  Like LC 75, LC 50, such 25.  Ok
?  This is how you can select.
Correct?  Now how will they be selected?
I will tell you this in the next video
because the video has become very long.
Today my only intention was to show you
that you
can get up to 15% annual return even within NPS.  How
can they take it?  You can do this by changing the fund manager and
changing your choices.
Ok?  So this way we saw
how we can get 15% annual return
under NPS.  Ok
?  But I will bring part two in the next video.
In the next video, I will
tell you how you can
change your fund manager.  I will
come live and show you.
How can you change your fund manager?
How can you change your choices?
Ok?  So do not forget to watch our next
part two video
because that video is going to be
very important for you people
because right now the
possibility of gradual rise in the stock market has also
increased.  Ok?  So with these words
I end this video here.  Hail
India.